Typhoon #13 is maintaining
its extremely strong force
as it continues making its way up north.
The storm area struck South Daitou
Island last night at around 11 p.m.
As of now, the effect on
transportation in all areas...
Daikichi!
The TV says the Shinkansen is pooping!
Not pooping! Operating!
[ Note: unko suru = pooping,
unkou suru = in operation ]
Pooping?
Operating!
They probably said, "The Shinkansen
is operating on normal schedules."
That means it's running same as usual.
The Shinkansen is pooping!
I'm gonna go poop!
Jeez...
Typhoon #13 has changed course
and is gradually moving east,
where it's expected to make
landfall in the Tokai area
sometime between this
evening and tonight.
She said there's a typhoon!
It's all right. Typhoons
come every year...
Daikichi!
Are you out of TP?!
You should see how much I'm making!
Bring a ruler!
Boys are notoriously childish, but...
I can empathize.
I dunno about tomorrow.
It's different than a sacrifice. Something's off.
I don't think it's like some penalty game.
So, why? I don't get it at all.
I'm a little bit unsatisfied, but your presence
right now is more than just important.
There's no such thing in this world
as something never-ending.
Crying isn't painful, it's love's sweet drops, sweet drops!
I want to keep dreaming forever, ya know?
I want to be more kind, ya know?
As long as I’m with you, I’m happy.
Girls sure are strong, ya know?
But sometimes we're weak, ya know?
Our wish is to be happy, happy, happy!
And those days will be happy, too!
Just wanna make you happy!
I'll pick you up early today.
Okay!
Kouki-kun, let's go!
Awesome, right?!
We're gonna be late.
See ya later!
If you leave just enough
space for the circles,
it means you've written
it in a cool way.
Got it?
Sensei, how much is "just enough"?
Um...
How many centimeters?
How many millimeters?
You don't have to draw these circles!
Okay!
All right, the rest
will be your homework.
For the next activity, all the
first-graders are going to draw.
Meet up outside in front
of your own morning glory.
Do you understand?
Yes!
Sandbags are that heavy?!
It's still morning and
I'm already beat...
And it had to be on a day like today
that we've got tons of samples to ship...
Thank you.
What's that?
My kids' educational insurance...
Your kids are still babies!
If I waited 'til they got bigger,
the insurance wouldn't mean a thing.
G-Good point.
We're enrolled too.
Even though I kinda doubt he'll be
college material, being my kid...
We got two, so it's pretty tight.
Ours is still a little squirt,
so we got day-care fees too,
which is nothin' to sneeze at.
And he outgrows his clothes like that...
Well, we're only contract
employees, but it helps
that the welfare pension program
and health insurance are included.
How about life insurance?
My wife took care of
that behind my back.
For mine, the payout is
decent if I kick the bucket,
but she has universal life insurance.
The basic one...
You guys really are "Dads", aren't you?
I'm impressed.
There's nothin' to be impressed about.
I wonder how much insurance costs...
The brat next door is so
frickin' noisy, we wanna move,
but the money just ain't there.
Yeah, I don't even know
what I'm workin' for...
Take a good look at us!
You get married, this is what happens!
I don't have a girlfriend,
so no danger of that.
They're always bitching
and moaning, and yet...
Deep down, there's a
sense of security...
I can't imagine them
becoming like Rin's mother.
Kouki-san!
Sit down and draw!
Yikes!
What about your drawing board?
Eh... The ground is flat,
so I don't need it.
That's not gonna float!
When I tell you to bring
something, you bring it!
Get it right now! Run!
Wow, your drawing is
really good, Rin-chan!
Yeah, it is! That's great!
It's pretty!
I don't know...
That really is good!
The colors of this flower and this
flower are slightly different,
and Rin-san's drawing shows that with
both bluish and purplish colors.
You have a sharp eye.
Kouki-kun and those boys
are wandering around again.
Kouki-san...
Right now, it's drawing time.
Kouki-san, your morning
glories are looking splendid!
It would be a waste not to sketch them.
Kouki-san, do you like drawing?
So-so, I guess...
Tatsumi-sensei...
I'm in charge of this boy.
Kouki-san, why do you always,
always disturb everyone?!
Now sit down and draw!
And don't make a weird face!
I got Kouki's hat!
Cut it out!
Hey! Kouki-san! Boys!
Stop fooling around!
Get back here!
I got it! I got it!
Rin-chan?
Kouki-kun!
Sit down and draw!
Don't let them get you in trouble!
Okay.
That was incredible, Rin-chan.
Kouki-kun always does strange stuff and
he's scary when he loses his temper.
Rin-chan, he'll bully you!
No, he won't! After all, we went
to the same nursery school.
Really?!
They're late...
You guys pick up your
kids at 6 too, right?
Yeah. Cuttin' it close today.
Here they are!
All right! Let's get it done in one!
Yeah!
Hello!
You got a little wet, huh?
Rin-chan! Your father's here!
Hey...
I-I'm sorry...
Not at all. Don't worry about it.
I'll go get Rin-chan.
The wind's really picked up, huh?
Yes. I wish I could've
gotten here earlier, but...
Am I the last?
Kouki-kun is here, too...
Daikichi!
There's a storm, huh?
Yeah. It's really coming down.
Sorry I'm late.
It's okay.
An umbrella's flying!
Did something happen?
Uh-uh. I'm fine.
See ya!
See you later, Kouki!
Wanna walk home together?
Let's walk home together!
Sure!
I'm sorry, but it's already decided
how he gets home, so we can't...
I know. But the wind is only
to keep getting stronger,
so let me try calling Nitani-san
and see if it would be a problem.
Then, just to confirm, can I
hand the phone over to you?
Um... In that case...
We can go home early, too!
What's that?!
Well, we were just kidding.
Kouki!
Me too!
Rin!
That's dangerous!
Get behind me and follow along!
Hold it!
I'll bring you a towel.
The storm windows!
Cool! Let me do it!
Careful, don't catch your fingers.
It's dark!
Y'know, it's kind of like a secret base!
It's in my eyes!
I'm gonna rinse it now,
so don't open your eyes.
All right, dry the rest yourself.
Daikichi, your back is huge!
I know, right?!
Good evening! It's Nitani!
Yes! I'll be right there!
So you were able to
get off work early...
I feel like I overstepped my bounds.
Not at all! It was a big help.
Sorry. Kouki got soaked
on the way here, too.
Really, I don't know where
to begin to apologize...
That looks good on you!
Daikichi, let me borrow yours!
Again with that?! You say,
"Daikichi-san", right?!
He said "Daikichi" is fine!
Yeah, I'm more comfortable with that.
That's right!
Just "Daikichi" is fine!
Rin-chan, you're good at that!
I can use a knife, too!
You're already a young lady!
Daikichi does the fire, though.
I'll do it too!
You never help out...
I'll cut too!
I'll lend you my knife!
Oh, no! Onions are dangerous!
Don't touch! Wash your eyes right away!
Where are you going?
Oh, no! I'm crying!
You're making hamburger patties...
Yep... It looks delicious, doesn't it?
These are kind of strange...
They're not strange! Right?
Well, I'm sure they'll taste fine.
Rin-chan! The eggs are boiled!
Please peel them!
Okay!
Here!
You're so good at that!
Rin is eating it up...
Kouki, do you love your mom?
If only she weren't such an old nag...
There's a sense of security here, too.
This one's mine!
What about giving thanks?
Thank you for the food
we're about to eat!
Kouki, use your chopsticks!
I know, I'm just getting it together.
It's good, isn't it?!
It is good!
Food tastes better when
we eat it together!
Let's eat here again tomorrow night!
Kouki!
That's good enough.
I'll finish up later.
Okay...
And then it hit him right in the head!
He's so excited...
I was never able to give him this
kind of opportunity 'til now.
I'm so happy about this evening.
Thank you.
Oh, I didn't... I need to thank you!
Sensei said we didn't
need those circles!
Being able to see that face...
I'm glad I got off work early.
She's raising a child alone, too...
Daikichi! Come here a second!
All right...
Well, I think it's about time...
Shall I call a taxi?
Yes, thank you.
Why don't you stay over?
Rin!
After all, Reina-chan
and her mom stayed over.
That was different!
See ya tomorrow...
See you!
Bye-bye!
Rin-chan, thank you.
Thank you very much.
We had fun, too.
Right?
Uh-huh!
Bye-bye!
A sunny early Sunday afternoon
Let's go somewhere today
It's the same road I'm used to traveling
But I can see it sparkling so bright
With the sun shining down its warmth
And you here by my side...
I'm already high, high, high
I feel like dashing out
Sing, la, la, la
My voice out to forever
I'm already high, high, high
Ride the dancing wind
Sing, la, la, la
My voice springs up
The typhoon left, huh?
Yep.
Rin-chan! Rin-chan!
Kouki-kun is here already!
He's early again!
Come on in!
Are you sure?
Hold on!
Wait!
I wanted to open the storm windows...
Not a cloud in the sky!
See you later!
Kouki-kun, we're gonna be late!
See ya later!